William Shultz

william.shultz2017@gmail.com | shultzwilliam.github.io | linkedin.com/in/wilshultz/ (330) 550-1705 | Atlanta, GA

Summary

Highly motivated and experienced Front-end Developer at SimplePart LLC, with a B.S in Computer Science and Engineering from The University of Toledo. Currently obtaining a M.S in Computer Science at the Georgia Institute of Technology. Proficient in Vue, .NET, MS SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap CSS, LESS, and experienced in building high-impact, responsive, revenue-generating websites.

Work Experience

SimplePart LLC | Atlanta, GA

Front-end Developer | Feb. 2023 - Present

- Collaborated with a team to design and implement cutting-edge stylings and components for over a dozen high-impact e-commerce sites, resulting in millions in revenue.
- Leveraged expertise in LESS and Bootstrap CSS to create visually appealing and responsive front-end stylings, while utilizing ASP.NET, VUE, and .NET to develop efficient and dynamic user interfaces backed by a robust backend infrastructure.

Full-stack Developer | Sept. 2023 - Feb. 2023

- Utilized ASP.NET, .NET, and MS SQL to develop comprehensive full-stack components, contributing to the successful delivery of projects.
- Demonstrated a proactive approach by responding to critical incidents promptly, mitigating potential revenue loss, and effectively collaborated within a fast-paced agile software environment to achieve project milestones.

Meta Reality Labs | Pittsburgh, PA

System Integrator | Apr. 2022 - Jul. 2022

- Developed and maintained data collection automation tools using Python and Bash, streamlining processes and enhancing efficiency.
- Implemented reusable unit test documents, contributing to improved quality control and a 10% increase in data capture success rates through effective collaboration with system engineers.

The University of Toledo | Toledo, OH

Undergraduate Researcher | May 2019 - Aug. 2021

- Created a method for calculating reflections off solar arrays using Python scripting.
- Presented research at IEEE conference in the summer of 2020 and published January 2021.
- Contributed to a \$30 million project funded by the U.S. Air Force Research Lab, titled "Assured Digital Microelectronics Education and Training Ecosystem".

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology | Atlanta, GA

M.S in Computer Science | Aug. 2023 - Present

The University of Toledo | Toledo, OH

B.S, Computer Science and Engineering | Sept. 2017 - Dec. 2021